hello
periscope three people we have one
person we have one person two people the
Tesla says all right so I think we
should kind of go through this all right
because this is kind of a lot of what I
see is wrong with how modern companies
communicate I'm so changing the world
with with AV that's all great this guy
then you have a big a big a big
statement cautionary note on
forward-looking statements basically
it's saying like we can't predict the
future right so this is this is like
thing one no right this is this
shouldn't have to be a thing I'm not
sure what kind of world we live in where
it's like you have to make a claim that
we cannot predict them but let's move on
GM's world you know I'm not gonna be
able to do this that well because I was
just I was just talking about it with
Vivian and like why something like this
is absurd so you know if you have
something like the trade-off between
socialism and libertarianism there's
arguments to be made on both sides right
if you have like a trade-off between
cameras and lidar there's arguments to
be made on both sides and you could have
a camera you could have a company that's
committed to cameras are committed to
light our committed to socialism
committed to libertarianism but in order
for that to like make any sense you need
to have like a reasonable not like a
like a really stupid straw man you would
need I'm gonna go reasonable you know
thing that you are in order for you to
be saying anything you have to be able
to reasonably imagine
somebody's saying the opposite right so
let's look at these things zero crashes
zero emission zero congestion so good
could you imagine somebody coming out in
favor of crashes good good boy could you
imagine some company coming out saying
well yeah like that's not a everything
in engineering and this is Yuma shows
you that these people aren't engineers
they don't think like engineers is about
trade-offs right if you're designing a
microprocessor you make a trade-off
between say speed and power or you can
make trade-offs between like reliability
and cost engineering is all about
trade-offs I'm not sure what this is
right everybody who wants there to be
zero crashes but to say like gee I was
worldview like this is actually a unique
and distinctive worldview it's not this
says nothing zero emissions zero
congestion nobody wants those things
right even you might have some people
who may not care about emissions but but
they're not opposed to zero it's
something that like everybody knows is
better this is not this is saying
nothing we are redefining the future of
personal mobility right so you then go
through all of these things and I mean
they're not these are all different
companies you talk about electric
vehicles maybe you have like Tesla's the
leader you talk about autonomous
vehicles maybe have way mostly there you
talk about shared mobility maybe you
have Ober is the leader I'm not okay but
I read about it so these sort of things
yeah committed to the future of strong
cores the foundation for investing in
the future electrification um so here's
another interesting thing that I noted
in here where they talk about Eevee is
the foundation for autonomous vehicles
up why because it supports our zero
emissions future again your companies
are not being led by engineers and this
is why you will lose
um you know or they say like there is no
AV without Evie I mean of course there
is right look WAY Moe's doing it right
way most Pacifica they're hybrids but
autonomous vehicles are very different
from electric vehicles because if you
had one autonomous vehicle it would be
incredibly useful just having you in one
autonomous vehicle is useful having you
in one electric vehicle is not that
useful because you need infrastructure
to support it so sometimes I think to
say things very quickly like you know
Evie is a shared infrastructure problem
but it is you don't need infrastructure
to support autonomous vehicles and it's
important to notice all the people out
there talking about like V to V and V to
I you actually need you you yeah
electric vehicles of course the main
thing that you need is is charging
stations so unless you have quick
charging stations like even if you have
a car that's capable of charging in five
minutes
when you look at how many megawatts of
power you'd have to pump through the
thing but this isn't gonna be that long
let's let's see Lea my AV strategy right
uh you know traffic fatalities are
caused by human error everyone knows
that parking okay we believe all a V's
must be V's on I have no idea why that
like are you making an argument here or
these just like statements independent
you know what else does this like TED
Talks you ever see that like and when I
press this button words will appear on
the screen so let's see if they get into
the technology Batman look at that lines
will go up bad lines will go down but
most lines will go up Oh
okay first mover escape velocity your
transportation service again um the
transportation of the service I'm not
really sure why autonomous vehicles make
transportation as a service cheaper but
I'm not sure there is some truly
critical threshold for it's the reason a
lot more people for a lot of people
using uber would be cheaper than then
car ownership but they're not making a
rational evaluation about this they're
not making like a rational decision
because most purchases are irrational
does a huge advertising business which
support this um so they're still talking
about how they're gonna do any of this
safety is the gating metric yeah okay
sure sure sure
GM is uniquely positioned in the IRT as
I say the word uniqueness in this in
this presentation oh okay so it's so
execution um talent is the foundation
right
so so when you brag about talent you
brag about how you've recruited people
from uber and Google boo at Google our
competitors in this space how do you win
if you are bragging about it's okay
there's lots of ways you could you can
still win but you need you need
something else right um and I'll explain
a concept in in in poker called called
domination and domination basically are
look like if your hand is ace king this
is a pretty good hand to have unless
somebody else at the table has baseness
alright this is Texas Hold'em if seventy
nine wow people are into this man okay
so so listen if flop comes over right
let's say let's say so so figured you
have a go-go player one sitting here
with an ace and your player two sitting
here with a scam right um if the flop
comes over and there's an ace on the
flop let's say
something like ace seven six right
player 2 thinks through in a good
position to aces but they're really not
because player 1 has has three aces
right let's even say it it's Kings at
six right player two still believes that
they are in a good position
even though player 1 is right now
player 3 is of course sitting at the
table with you know eight nine eight
nine maybe there are suited connectors
right player three is in a better
position than player two right because
think about how many outs player 2 has
versus how many outs player three has
even if they came up the only real way
player 2 wins this not with another ace
right another ace player 3 is three of a
kind to two pair but even if another
king comes up that's the the only way
player 2 can win as if a king comes up
right versus player three which could
win of either a a 10 or 5 cuts I write a
lot their strengths minister it's gonna
be so you do not want to be player 2 and
I'll mark you why Cruz is player 2 right
now all components need to be six I
developed for a successful launch right
the problem is the exact same slide
exists at lame-o but way mo has more of
these boxes filled in you know I'm
really hoping like like why am I doing
this
I'm really hoping some investors will be
able to hopefully like start to
critically evaluate what this space
looks like and realized why if you're
the Ace King if you're saying I'm going
to build what way mo is building how are
you going to beat way mo so you know
silver bullet for AV technology I mean
really that's at least a statement
that's at least a statement where
something's being said it's
but their compote is an engineer this is
a section right he is he is an engineer
you can tell that he's thinking like an
engineer because he's making statements
that have another like you you can argue
the other side right now I'm not saying
your side is wrong but you are wrong by
default if there is no other side or
you're not even wrong you're just saying
nothing and this is something that
everybody should use when they evaluate
anything in the world right like think
about the other position and whether
it's a viable position right if people
stopped like like likley please start
evaluating what is being said right and
now you'll think about the other side
and don't attribute Mouse to the other
side if there is another side right but
if there is no this type realize you're
saying nothing cool
so no silver bullet for a check for any
technology I mean maybe there is right
there was a silver bullet for a girl
playing I mean maybe now I'll get into
I'll do a little bit of contrasting this
with what comma believes um so there was
a silver bullet for go playing right if
you can you can kind of think of all the
same stuff if you are trying to build a
go agent you can imagine a company
trying to build a go agent um you know
they're like well okay so we're gonna do
some sort of some awesome some endgame
study some some opening moves study some
jokes Seki study you right and the truth
is that none of this matter at all I
mean in fact so much didn't matter at
all that you didn't even need the
historical data you just needed to build
one maybe a silver bullet your magical
reinforcement learning algorithm and
alphago zero so this is a this is a this
is a state and maybe it wasn't even made
this way maybe it wasn't even made as a
statement that could have another side
argue but I will argue the other side
and I will argue that the silver bullet
for maybe technology is reinforcement
learning is is sophisticated machine
learning because we if you we live in
the alphago's 0 world that changed the
world um deep simulation capability
right
does Cruz think their simulator is
better than huevos when was this thing
called car crafter it's a very
sophisticated simulator um best
simulator in the world right now
great simulator wish I had access to it
right just cruise think they're they're
simulators better than weightless right
um HD map they can route it who's miss
mafic company in the world
what are you use Maps well you use you
use one of three everybody pretty much
uses one of three you're either using
Google Maps ways or Apple Maps and
you're not using Apple maps cuz it's
your first choice you're using Apple
house cuz it came to your iPhone um
Google Maps and ways are actually owned
by the same company called Google which
is also my alphabet which is the same
company that also owns way mode right so
so who is the best HD mapping and
routing company in the world
Google proprietary AV sensors okay so so
now you're telling me you're gonna build
custom light so so so so let's talk
about the three things we have
simulation mapping and light swipe these
on the right that's really that's really
because this is this is like a strategy
for maybe company right maybe I should
have kept the poker hands on the board
because that really is the analogy um
you know your simulation mapping
and so this is one path to self-driving
cars um it might be the right path I'm
not arguing like like like whether it's
the right path or the wrong path can be
argued on the other side might way mom
win self-driving cars I think it's way
mo loses I mean they have a huge
technology lead right now they Google
has a notorious problem with rolling
things out maybe this is somewhat what
Cruz is betting on but you're in a very
bad position if you're counting on your
opponent to make a mistake right if
you're counting on your if you have like
a fundamentally different strategy from
air quality you're in a much better
position than if you're counting on your
opponent to mess up I never would plays
chess or any sort of strategy game knows
this right you don't want to keep your
down pieces you're like but I know that
week I know they're gonna they're gonna
stupidly lose they're wrong and he may
be but when you look at advantage right
now advantage Google advantage Google
advantage Google so maybe maybe maybe
execution has advantage Cruz but you're
arguing
it's an execution by them by do it
excuse me
hmm does actually know how to ship cars
and the way mouth you know builds like
satin they built their own for each
other it's not well Scott right
I don't think GM cars are great but if I
had a choice between are you like I
would remember that time for the Chevy
Cobalt
forty thousand dollar card it doesn't
power seats it has that it has a
eight-inch resistive touchscreen like
really about my model three minute I
want to model to if anyone out there was
to some new model three moment but um
yeah but you're fundamentally like
execution kind of has inhabitant
right - you're counting on your opponent
to make a mistake of your cruise so
maybe this is the you know traditional
right um now there's another stack the
other stack is the amount stack and this
is kind of where comma lies and we're
testing lies so if you think about big
data and machine now you can of course
like the same argument for for comma and
Tesla between between Google Cruz are
you talking about I tell actually both
the advantages here um but we
acknowledge this fact right and the idea
is Tesla has a disadvantage Tesla has a
substantial disadvantage and Tesla's
disadvantages the following proprietor I
don't know how to spell that word so say
it's a less and they also had easy use
right so if you believe the following
two things about Tesla if you believe
that Tesla's never go into licensed
autopilot technology probably pretty
likely um then you can talk about you
know this is working okay for comma and
you can also believe that Tesla will
never build non electrical um and the
thing here is autonomous is going to
happen before electric because of that
network effect that I talked about
before
about how we can't have the advantage
here because I mean you know my zero
emissions I'm a fan of zero emissions
too but you know it's not my worldview
right so let's go back to the this is
really the main point I want to make
right like how are you going to be
justice Google Google understands their
execution problem like at least they
understand what their own mistake so
they can bring it out of a car company
CEO they brought me on that guy you know
you watching the robot summon is that
right he's right he understands where
Google's previous failings are now if I
were label of course but I would be
doing is I would open that the Pacifica
platform all right now to people right
just just just do it man just ship it
you know who actually this firm we
talked about some time in the office
right imagine instead of Google Fiber it
was called uber fiber you know that
would be everywhere they'd be crushing
ISPs left and right Comcast would be in
a corner crying like the taxi companies
are right now that's why we slap Comcast
don't interrupt our service Comcast yeah
we pay on time oh we pay on time cool
yeah so yeah yeah yeah yeah I go to
market are ok so this uh this go to
market again it's the exact same slides
right now that way my eyes right this is
literally way most for requirements for
launching as well um anchored by
valuable franchises yeah China Australia
right business business business
business business business I cool things
that nobody understands in disclaim okay
cool um but yeah do you have questions
not really people are excited
for uber fiber fiber is gonna be sick
man yep
whoever I was gonna be sick some someone
has before Colliver sway my like why why
do you think that's dead well okay so
you can talk about the traditional stack
or the ml stack right um which one of
these wins is it yet to be discovered
fact about the world
um maybe maybe this is even like like
lidar versus cameras right it's not uh
we don't know yet which approach wins so
comment is a bet comment is a bet comma
I mean to be fair way Moe's got the Aces
and we got the the nine-eight of course
of course when most got the Aces cruises
the Ace King we get their name right so
we go back to my poker analogy here the
nice thing about you know waynebow was
valued at uh at 10 billion dollars and
they become as valued at 200 million so
that's that's uh that's a pretty big
differential we're talking about you
know 500 x right 500 x is actually a lot
lower than the real odds of winning
these hands all right so I'm fun to do
for nine day I just don't have these
camera I really don't have any use king
of the stairs a scheme has very few outs
when someone at the table is holding is
holding places I could flush to or you
know that guy doesn't know any updates
for new users I want to convert to um Oh
converting you're gonna buy any on that
have you come on conversions come on I
mean this here's what I say about music
I know some NGOs that I feel about rugby
Tampa's reveille pandas right now still
work
Neos will continue to work they just
won't be officially supported it won't
be tested they won't be but we're not
gonna do anything to gratuitously break
right it's not like you always want to
be always wonder it's like an apple
they do they make it looks like very
difficult to run on it oh yeah there's a
physical build Nate's talking in town
sounds good Hey look man in town
you guys keep building faster processors
and we'll keep building slower operating
systems so yeah I mean what what are
what are our advantages over Tesla you
see like the equipment is if way mo wins
and beats crews they beat crews if Tesla
Widow really launches their service a
year before crews has a service ready to
launch they'd have to be the dumbest
people in history to not be able to
scale that up and to not be able to like
come on that's an easy problem compared
to like the technical engineering
probably software right if Tesla wins
and thoroughly wins we went to we went
to in the same way
iOS is never going to have 95 percent
market share because iPhones are too
expensive and they're only supported
well they're supported by one company
and they guess there's no real
corresponding infrastructure problem and
there's no fundamental reason that Apple
won't build things that might look like
Android phones right which is why what
you see in the iOS and so why is comma
different from way mo because we're
trying to completely different approach
whether this approach or this approach
wins remains to be seen this is a fact
yet to be discovered about the world and
whether Tesla or comma wins I argue that
there's no income losses even if Tesla
crushes it even if Tesla in fact there
Tesla autopilot like you know by the end
of this year is level 3 thank you for
the existence proof right thank you for
telling me that I know I can build
something that good right even if I
don't know how it works just kind of
know it makes it a little bit easier you
kind of think okay well I know that
works I'm sure I can figure out how to
do that all right you see this in
science all the time you see that things
get discovered really really close to
each other so yeah if Tesla wins , wins
if Weibo wins
I just don't really see it right I was
GM wants to of course sell cars to
Google and below dealership prices they
went a little can keep the temper set
margins while you can right look at the
Bob Liberty does it wobble over deal
right do you want to be Volvo in that
deal you just got a huge purchase order
and to be fair you're now Foxconn right
that's what this one doesn't have any
phones to be phone makers that really
wanted to differentiate themselves with
software lost and phone makers that were
like we're just gonna build really nice
Hardware one black bear you're gone
Samsung was doing great
LG is doing all right but remember the
phone Samsung and LG used to make these
to make the crappiest flip phones 2006
any other questions nope eighty-six
viewers then 86 viewers we should we
should convert these we should like try
like play an ad right now and like
periscope will pay me all right this is
a comedy on comet eons are the
replacement for your car dashboard it's
everything you should have wanted and
you're kind of unfortunately this comet
Aeon doesn't have any software in it
because it's a very impromptu
advertisement but this is a great
universal computing platform for your
car this is really don't get yours it'll
have something when you have you doing
you guys one song we don'twe this song
isn't something where's the software
game yeah this is the
yes um is it panda pandas are universal
car interfaces um they turn car ports
that look like this into is everybody
leaving because it's a happening we have
more people with people about like SUV
Honda Odysseys Oh Honda Odyssey which
has the upside-down connector oh no I
mean it works it kind of works yeah let
let let some other people kind of figure
out the Odyssey first be connectors
literally upside down so the giraffe
doesn't physically fit in the car it's
ridiculous it's they probably did that
on purpose they never attribute to
malice but you can tune on in confidence
oh by the way this is not sold as a
self-driving car kit none of this stuff
is sold as a self-driving car kit we
sell dash cams and minor car peripherals
we give away free software which which
is a driving agent Honda Accord the new
Honda Accord is gonna be easier to do in
the old Honda Accord the old Honda
Accord used this weird L cast hearing
the 2018 hotter chord actually every
Honda Accord comes with I think they're
still calling about a sensing so yeah
it's a panda
there are $99 they convert this plug
which is available on every car made
after 1996 well what you're good we got
a hyper that's this is great this is
great yeah um you got to stay with us
for the rest of the and after this break
we'll tell you who gets the roads will
tell you oh cool so this is a yeah I've
got Wi-Fi USB bridges your car two
things that look like computers phones
of course look like computers keeps in
the future yeah you can do it yourself
man it's open source comma officially
will support Honda's and Toyota's
everything else is gonna be community
supported but you seen pretty good
community support does one last serve
all speaking of community support we've
got a tour coming up oh well no no we'll
get there we haven't we got an advertise
for the last thing we saw the responding
30 product today so that product yeah we
have a fourth product - I don't have one
where's my hoodie oh people are asking
about shirts are we gonna sell no we
only sell hoodies and they're only over
part No oh is that a hoodie yeah yeah no
this is an old one this is an old buddy
no no you're not gonna you're getting
you get much nicer orders man um yeah no
yeah we got hats bro we got hats yeah
yeah you know I feel like I feel like ah
so the giraffe giraffes connect pandas
even deeper into your car this
connectors are available on a lot of
Toyotas are you pan down like this like
your connector in like this and then of
course you have here a USB cable I'm
going here your panda we're
mass-producing he owns right now yeah
just place it like that be an excellent
dad yeah okay let's talk about our tour
cool um so it starts we're gonna have a
kickoff event for the press who doesn't
know about this yet but um we're having
a kickoff event on the 14th to kick off
self-driving car Awareness Week
self-driving car worship leave that like
on the board that should always be there
should always be there so on the 14th
we're gonna have the kickoff for self s
pellet right I'm really bad at like
writing with like a penny driving car
awareness we terrible marker you know
you know what know who else you know
would still be CEO of his company if it
was profitable who would so we see you
as a company of those profitable with
Travis yes
this is dedicated to Travis and I
seriously hope you doing Walter yeah
I'm a big fan Hoover's done so much good
for the world so much so much good ice
cream truck music like lick were like
been aggressive and push it out to every
city no way man you needed someone to
beat those taxis up yeah
so I'm 14th we're having a press event
um and yeah we're gonna let the press
drive our alright we're calling them
demonstration units demonstration use to
demonstrate our open source software
open Pi and then we will be traveling
across the country all right so we are
right here in the middle of the country
people think of San Francisco being
north but it's not really this is where
we're starting for the self-driving car
awareness to we're gonna be driving
across the country all the way back to
11:00 for a never-before-seen event or
tour that's right yes right
never-before-seen we're gonna be driving
from San Francisco to to New Jersey in a
self-driving car we're gonna be doing a
lot of periscoping to make sure that can
you follow on periscope or is there word
Twitter's orders following so follow on
yeah and that gets tuned in tuned in
then follow his ass like Twitter what a
good line what are you like yeah cool so
we're gonna be we're gonna be plowing
through California to Nevada really
boring here's like Reno I don't think
we're stopping I know I've already spent
to Burning Man and stuff to green I went
too many times which was once we're
gonna fly through Nevada here or it
passed Windham you good you guys know
what am yuka you would not win a mucus
you drove to for gas a lot of times
actually there's one great thing in
Nevada and that's down here that's Las
Vegas but we won't be going on and what
we want to LA this weekend for nips
though here oh that's good because we're
not going to land a lot of people ask
about LA no that's just conference
that's saying so say guess I guess
there's Wyndham UK we're gonna fight to
win em you go and we're gonna stop right
here in Salt Lake City Salt Lake City is
the first stop on the self-driving car
awareness tour we're still followers so
people still watch this any point is
work that I worked for a man what kiss
blow us out better yeah what we're on
the periscope where we're showing for
this ultra now around this to it nice we
yeah we just ranted about the cruise
yeah was watching upstairs with Harold
this on that show
what
really reasonability I assume it was
like an eight-hour presentation or
something if I have to actually sit
there for that oh I like applaud for
like the GM executive he had GM except
nobody should let me around the company
we're getting distracted and we're
losing folks okay so it's the song so
slowly City and then we're gonna drive
over here to Kansas next agenda oh whoa
stopping in Denver Denver but we've
actually never tourists off the number
but we're not anywhere stun oh yeah yeah
we're chillin in Denver so purple we
will circle the tour stop in purple
right cool so don't went driving like
the long distance over here to Kansas
City Missouri campus it's the one knock
Hesston Kansas only Kansas City Missouri
yeah we're not going to Kansas yo one
time I was in Kansas City and it was
tax-free holiday but only in like one of
the states so I went to the Apple store
in that state part of Kansas City I'm
not the other state part of Kansas City
that's confusing it's true yeah all
right cool and then we're gonna be
making the trip up here oh I've never
actually done anything in Omaha yeah
you're slapping them to stop it on and
then a tour stop in Sioux oh oh well
this is gonna be hard I really can't let
go you X I really can't smell anything
without Google guys don't don't take us
in the general intelligence all right
and then we're going up north nor in the
apples oh well I guess I'm in the
apples hitch or something no nuts were
stopped let's go at the mall America
yeah
I was ready because that's new yeah you
know okay down over here to Chicago
yeah where we also wanted to talk to a
stop but we will it to a stop
in Pittsburgh burg with me okay not
Pittsburg California and then we're
gonna head down here Philly Philly Pitts
and definitely stopping and that's gonna
be the last stop on our tour and I will
drive home to New Jersey yep
so Philly happens on the total third Wow
so we have one two three four five six
stops as well as the press event in San
Francisco which you can kind of
extrapolate out from the 14th we're
gonna be publishing it it's gonna be
like warp tour man yeah you know what's
the last year Warped Tour it's the first
year of the sub driving awareness still
looking to minors we're still looking
for partners your crews do you want to
partner with some no but but enough but
seriously I'm gonna hear in any of these
cities you want to set up an event we'll
have the car there dude
live in Eddie from , also driven and
until Chicago are joining until Chicago
absolutely I'm so there will be the lead
three of us will all be in comic gear
we're gonna make up some nice software
and car where's tour t-shirt man I've
always wanted a tour the country like
little peep so now we're now we're doing
recipes yep but I've always wanted to in
country are so we're doing this as a
sovereign power we're just or we're
gonna have the self-driving car
available for people to try out how you
can try a self-driving car yes with come
AI you can hopefully we can have open
town 0.4 out by then when the software
team shows up resources enough yeah I
hope the software teams if I'm watching
this and we're all counting on them
we're all counting on them
that's right so yeah we're gonna that
out and we're gonna let you guys try it
and then we're also gonna have our dash
cam pandas and your apps available for
sale right on the spot we're gonna get
one of those little swipe ease so we can
have coordinators car readers s that's
the word we're gonna get one of those
then you guys you know what let me tell
you about starting a company I used to
say don't ever start a company but we're
amending that don't ever start a company
if you're not gonna have fun we gotta
have
man you know who's not having fun
whoever wrote that long legal disclaimer
in there someone's asking us zero point
three point nine when's that coming up
oh well almost everything would I cut
out touches on the list when that list
is done that yeah a little lunch it
would be good night my sadly not gonna
have a new model um I take that they're
failing for this but it should still be
pretty good cool any more questions
people are still alright alright guys up
tempo awareness to it thank you for
joining us on periscope and I hope you
have a great day thanks guys